### contact@trevorsuarez.com

# **Trevor N Suarez**

## Software Engineer (with a Backend Focus)

#### **INTRO**

Software Engineer with an obsession for detail. Open source advocate. Lover of tools. Constantly echoing the "Principle of least astonishment".

I want to design and develop unique, socially responsible, software (applications and tools) that positively affect the world. My passion lies in creating intuitive user experiences.

Quality over speed (...to a point). Sustainability and maintainability. Don't recreate the wheel, but construct new wheels with stronger and lighter materials.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **RemoteHQ** — Software Engineer

DEC 2018 - JAN 2020

Worked as part of a TINY (4 engineers max) team over the course of 13 months. Expanded the backend API framework while developing core features end-to-end.

Most time was spent writing Go, developing HTTP REST APIs, and creating new features, while efforting towards a self-documented, self-describing, wholly consistent resource interface.

Worked on a Vue.js/TypeScript front-end part-time there also.

All applications and services were containerized in Docker, using Docker Compose locally and AWS ECS in production.

# Robin Powered, Inc. — Engineer

MAR 2014 - DEC 2018

I spent most of my time engineering the platform backend.

Was the main contributor to the public/private Robin API, which was written on top of a framework that I initially created and then continued to develop with my team.

I also developed microservices in Go, including a SQS-based job queue executor.

Helped directly manage the platform's infrastructure in AWS, provisioning server images using Packer, Puppet, etc.

I also wrote the beta Android app.

# One Mighty Roar — Developer

JUN 2012 - DEC 2018

I worked with an eclectic, creative team, developing web and mobile applications and services for numerous clients.

# **Plymouth State University** — Junior Developer

AUG 2008 - JUL 2012

I was a Junior developer and part of the MIS group at the university. I worked on smaller parts of large products in a team environment and was also tasked with solo projects.

I was responsible for the creation of the original Plymouth State University cross-platform (iOS/Android) mobile app.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Plymouth State University, NH** – B.S. in Computer Science

2008 - 2012

Developed and released the official PSU Mobile app (Android and iOS) for my senior project while being mentored by the MIS team.

#### **PRIMARY SKILLS**

Go (Golang), PHP, TypeScript, JavaScript

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis

REST, gRPC, AWS (EC2, RDS, SQS)

Linux, Docker, Bash, Git

#### SECONDARY SKILLS

Java, Python, Dart

MongoDB

Vue.js, Android SDK

# **PROJECTS**

## retry - Go

A simple, stateless, functional mechanism to perform actions repetitively until successful.

Written as an exercise in creating a functional, clean, simple API design.

Used by Google (CadVisor), Canonical (Go-Dqlite), and WeWork (Grabbit)

# **define** – Go

A command-line dictionary (thesaurus) app, with access to multiple sources, written in Go.

# incoming - PHP

Transform loose and complex input into consistent, strongly-typed data structures.

# PHP NTLM - PHP

Message encoder/decoder and password hasher for NTLM.